Finding Aid for Wallace John Bonk papers, 1956-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wallace John Bonk papers 1956-1965
Bonk, Wallace John, 1923-
1.2 linear feet
8879 Aa 2
Professor of library science at the University of Michigan. Files relating to his work with the Teachers Section, Library Education Division, American Library Association.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The files were transferred from the University of Michigan School of Library Science (donor no. 4855 ). Additions came from the estate of Joyce Bonk (donor no. 3320 ) in 2012.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Wallace Bonk was professor of library science at the University of Michigan.
The Bonk collection relates only to his activities with the Teachers Section, Library Education Division, American Library Association. Included are minutes of meetings, correspondence; conference materials, and other subject files.
Subjects:
American Library Association. Library Education Division. Teachers Section.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Library Science.
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.; Photographs.
- American Library Association. Library Education Division. Teachers Section
  - Minutes of meetings, 1956-1964 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - January-May 1962 (Box 1)
    - June-September 1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963 (Box 1)
    - January-February 1964 (Box 1)
    - March 1964 (Box 1)
    - April-July 1964 (Box 1)
  - Conferences
    - Midwinter meeting (Chicago), 1962/1963 (Box 1)
    - Annual conference (Chicago), 1962/1963 (Box 1)
    - Midwinter meeting (Chicago), 1963/1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Annual conference (St. Louis), 1963/1964, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Midwinter meeting (Washington), 1964/1965, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Annual conference (Detroit), 1964/1965 (Box 1)
    - Annual conference (Detroit), 1964/1965 Executive Board (Box 1)
  - Committees
    - Annual reports, 1963/1964 (Box 1)
    - Nominating committee report, 1963/1964 (Box 1)
    - General, 1964/1965, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - L.E.D. office (Mrs. Kaufman), 1964/1965 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws (text and correspondence) (Box 1)
  - Media Research (Box 1)
  - Commission on a National Plan for Library Education (Box 1)
  - Newsletter (Box 1)
  - Membership lists (Box 1)
- 2012 Accession
  The 2012 Accession, mainly visual materials, include a photograph album of Wallace Bonk, with photos of military training at New Mexico School of Mines and Louisiana State University, along with family travel and his home town of Two Rivers, Wis. The accession also incldues a few other items, notably the score of a Christmas song by Louis Jolyon West inscribed by West to the Bonks.
  - Photograph album (Box 2)
  - Loose photos from album (Box 2)
  - Papers (Box 2)
  - Audiocassettes, 3 tapes (Box 2)